frequency energy.
>> This is an electrical device of [music]
some kind. Has to be magnetism or
frequency energy. Seven different
worlds. We are living in number eight
right here.
>> Okay.
>> He said right here, look this triangle.
So as above as is below.
>> Yinyang.
Of course, the orientation is going to
be very symbolic. [music]
It only cuts on with the anthropomorphic
figure right here looking up. You can
see the leads right here and also the
contacts right here.
[music]
have the neutral, the hot and the
ground. 120 is hot, neutral, ground. A
230 is hot, hot, ground. This is an
electrical device of some kind. Another
handbag.
>> [music]
>> This is 4,000 years old. You seen a
Bible?
>> This is older than the Bible. Yet, it
has this very Christian symbol in there.
That'll let you know that everything on
Earth is circular.
What he was saying is right here. This
is a symbol of the universe. These are
[music] the planets. Quanto 1 2 3 4 5 6
7 Mundos.
>> See
>> seven different worlds. We are living in
number [music] eight right here. If this
was fake, I think this would be center.
Look, it's not perfect. They're showing
you that this is not made in a factory.
>> [music]
>> If they could carve a rock like this, do
you think they could have squared that
up perfect? Of course they could have.
[music] There's not a single mistake in
any of this. Where's the oops? Where's
the Oh no. Where's the I up? I
don't see it.
>> Mhm.
>> This is what Arturo said. The artifacts
to be exhibited were found in region and
feature iconography that does not
directly correspond to known
Mesoamerican symbolic systems. Their
engravings, geometric patterns, and the
intentional arrangement of certain
elements suggest a highly civilized
technical and symbolic [music]
knowledge, the meaning of which is still
being studied. One of the most striking
aspects of [music] these pieces is the
presence of quartz deliberately
integrated into their structure. [music]
The quartz emits a visible luminescence.
This phenomenon does not occur
spontaneously nor randomly, but only
when the pieces are aligned and
connected under specific [music]
conditions.
All right. From a scientific
perspective, quartz is a material known
for its pioelectric properties and its
ability to interact with pressure,
mechanical energy, or energy fields
frequency. However, the way it was
worked and arranged in these artifacts
suggests an advanced understanding of
these properties applied with an
intention that goes beyond a mere
ornamentation. The symbols carved on the
surfaces could yet be related to an as
yet deciphered activation,
communication, or signaling system that
links form matter and energy. The light
generated when the pieces are joined
should not be interpreted as a random
effect, but rather as the physical
reaction that points to a premeditated
functional design. These findings open
new lines of research into the
technological [music] and conceptual
level of the cultures that inhabited
Tula or even earlier groups and raise
fundamental questions about the use of
mineral, energetic, and symbolic
knowledge in antiquity. Far from
offering definitive [music] answers,
these artifacts invite us to observe,
document, and analyze rigorously,
maintaining an open mind towards what we
do [music] not yet fully understand. I
think this fits the bill of do not fully
understand. [music]
Rocks that emit light endlessly, uh, no
battery attached. If somebody could help
me can figure out how this works, I
think it would be beneficial to the
human race and civilization as a whole.
Uh, Joe and Arturo signing out [music]
from sunny Florida.